# Michael Caplan, Software Development Manager Who Codes

me@michaelcaplan.com | https://www.michaelcaplan.com/ | Wolfville, Nova Scotia, CA

SUMMARY

Mike has been active as a web application developer and designer since the late 90s, working in the non-profit, university, retail, agricultural, and health care industries. He was a founding partner of HarvestHand, a platform that services Community Shared Agriculture farms. Mike founded Refresh Annapolis Valley, a new media professional association. Mike is the Software Development Manager for the Labnet Dental Lab Systems division of Henry Schein – a solutions company for health care professionals.

EXPERIENCE

Henry Schein One | Software Development Manager 2006-09-30 — Present The Labnet Dental Lab Systems division of Henry Schein One offers the Dental Lab industry's most comprehensive and powerful management systems; with solutions suited for labs of all sizes and budgets.

**HarvestHand** | Co-Founder & Software Developer 2010-12-31 - 2019-12-31 HarvestHand was an Internet platform for Community Shared Agriculture (CSA) businesses to communicate with and manage their community of members.

**Mom & Pop Media** | Founder and Software Developer 2000–12–31 — 2007–12–31 Working under the name Mom & Pop Media, I started my freelance web and print design consultancy upon return from my stay in South Africa in 2000.

**High-Touch Communications** | Senior Programmer 2005-12-31 — 2006-12-31 High-Touch Communications is a leading North American branding + web firm, offering its pièce de résistance web platform called IgnitionWeb.

**Le Château** | Lead PHP Developer

2004-01-01-2005-12-31

Le Château Inc. was a fashion company. I worked on developing a large scale corporate Intranet which integrated legacy systems and new web application solutions for over 300 users and 150 stores across Canada and the USA.

SKILLS

**Frontend Web Development** (Advanced): HTML5, CSS2+, jQuery, Vue.js, React, Bootstrap, Javascript, ECMAScript 2021

**Back End Web Development** (*Advanced*): PHP, Zend Certified Engineer, Zend Framework, Node.js, SQL

Web Applications Systems Architect and Administrator (Advanced): Ubuntu Server, CentOS, MySQL, MariaDB, Elasticsearch, Firebase Cloud Firestore, Apache HTTP Server, NGINX, Apache ActiveMQ, Zabbix Monitoring, OSSEC – Server Intrusion Detection, Wazuh – Open Source Security Platform, Ansible – Configuration Management, Client–Server, Multitiered Architecture, Event Driven, REST, Shared Nothing

**Software Engineering** (Advanced): Requirements gathering, Software architecture, Data design - ER modeling, Interface design, Design patterns, Unit Testing, Integration Testing

**Software Development Lifecycle** (*Advanced*): Git, Jira, Bitbucket, Kanban, Agile

**Software Design** (*Intermediate*): Design Thinking, User Research – Personas, Wireframing, Prototyping, Balsamiq, A/B Testing, End User Functional Testing

Entrepreneurship (Intermediate): Lean Canvas, Minimal viable product,

Continuous deployment

**Graphic Design** (*Intermediate*): Adobe Pagemaker, Adobe InDesign, Scribus, Inkscape

**Digital Marketing** (Intermediate): Content development, Press releases, Email, Social media. SEO

EDUCATION Dawson College

1992-09-01 — 1994-12-31

Degree - Graphic Design

 Apr 15, 2020

**Zend Certified Engineer: PHP 5** | Zend **Zend Certified Engineer: PHP 4** | Zend

Jan 6, 2008 Mar 31, 2005

Software Development for the World Wide Web | Concordia University

rsity Aug 31, 2001

**AWARDS** 

#### Agriculture Innovation Accelerator Award

2013-10-03

Annapolis Valley Chamber of Commerce

The award recognizes outstanding agriculture and agri-food related innovators including producers, processors, suppliers and organizations. The award was presented to HarvestHand.

First Place 2013-11-30

Halifax Startup Weekend

An event that brings entrepreneurial-minded people from different backgrounds and professions together to develop innovative start-ups in 54 hours.

Third Place 2017-03-24

Hacking Health Halifax

A weekend-long hackathon that breaks down barriers to healthcare innovation by bringing together IT and healthcare professionals to collaborate, dream up & design apps, devices and solutions for patient-centric care.

### VOLUNTEERING Hoist Annapolis Valley - Organizer | Refresh Annapolis Valley

https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/project/hoist/ 2017-03-13 — 2019-12-09 Hoist Annapolis Valley was a tech club for teens interested in coding, design and entrepreneurship. I organized monthly meetups, participation in competitions, developed curriculum, organized camps, and mentored youth.

**#Scratchfest - Organizer** | Refresh Annapolis Valley 2017-04-24 — 2019-04-07 https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/event/scratchfest-2019/

#ScratchFest was a weekend Build-a-thon for kids and teens interested in creating amazing original work with digital technologies, such as the Scratch programming environment, Processing, Virtual Reality, and more.

#### Creative Computing - Leader | Refresh Annapolis Valley

https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/project/creative- 2017-01-31 — 2019-06-30 computing/

Creative Computing was a course as well as a Summer camp that focused on exposing kids to the computer sciences. The course used the popular Scratch programming environment, as well as other platforms, to aid young people (aged 8 to 13) in learning the basics of software development.

## Founder and Organizational Crew | Refresh Annapolis Valley

https://refreshannapolisvalley.org/

2012-12-31 — 2020-12-31

A community of designers, developers, and innovators working to refresh the creative, technical, and professional culture of digital technology endeavours in the Annapolis Valley while promoting design, technology, and entrepreneurship.